export let questions=
[
{
question:"Which of the following are the most and the least electronegative elements in the periodic table?",
a:" Fluorine and Caesium",
b:"Hydrogen and Helium",
c:"Carbon and Oxygen",
d:"Chlorine and Fluorine",
correct:"a"
},
{
question:"Which among the following methods can be used to remove the permanent hardness in water due to calcium or magnesium sulphates?",
a:"Sulphonate method",
b:"Nitrate method",
c:"Zeolite method",  
d:"None of these",
correct:"c"
},
{
question:"What happens to the weight of Iron, when it rusts?",
a:'Increases for long time',
b:'Decreases then increases',
c:'Increases then decreases',
d:'Remains the same',
correct:"c"
},
{
question:"Which of the following is not a metalloid?",
a:"Boron",
b:"Silicon",
c:"Germanium",
d:"Titanium",
correct:"d"
},
{
question:"In which form is the work done in stretching a wire stored as?",
a:"Kinetic energy",
b:"Potential energy",
c:"Heat energy",
d:"Electrical energy",
correct:"b"
},
{
question:"Which computer program converts assembly language to machine language?",
a:"Interpreter",
b:"Compiler",
c:"Assembler",
d:"Comparator",
correct:"c"
},
{
question:"A folder in windows computer can't be made with name?",
a:"can",
b:"con",
c:"mak",
d:"make",
correct:"b"
},
{
question:"A computer use which type of number system to calculate and to store data?",
a:"decimal",
b:"octal",
c:"binary",
d:"hexadecimal",
correct:"c"
},
{
question:"What is the extension type of the excel 2007 files?",
a:".xls",
b:".xlsx",
c:".xsl",
d:"None of the above",
correct:"b"
},
{
question:"In which form is the work done in stretching a wire stored as?",
a:"Kinetic energy",
b:"Potential energy",
c:"Heat energy",
d:"Electrical energy",
correct:"b"
},
{
question:"Main circuit board in a computer is:",
a:"Decoder",
b:"Highlight",
c:"Select",
d:"Mother board",
correct:"d"
},
{
question:'Who penned the book "Wings Of Fire"?',
a:"Jawaharlal Nehru",
b:"APJ Abdul Kalam",
c:"Dr. B. R. Ambedkar",
d:"Indira Gandhi",
correct:"b"
},
{
question:'When is International Mother Language Day celebrated?',
a:"21 February",
b:"31 March",
c:"28 June",
d:"21 October",
correct:"a"
},
{
question:'Who opened the first school for girls in India?',
a:"Bhimrao Ramji Ambedkar",
b:"Savitribhai Phule",
c:"Vijay Lakshmi Pandit",
d:"Indira Gandhi",
correct:"b"
},
{
question:'Who is known as the missile woman of India?',
a:"Tessy Thomas",
b:"Savitribhai Phule",
c:"Indira Gandhi",
d:"None of the above",
correct:"a"
},
{
question:"In which year did the massacre of Jallianwala Bagh occur?",
a:"1919",
b:"1927",
c:"1931",
d:"1943",
correct:"a"
},
{
question:"How many years did it take to build the Taj Mahal?",
a:"30 years",
b:"15 years",
c:"20 years",
d:"None of the above",
correct:"c"
},
{
question:"What is the name of the oldest known civilization found in the Indian subcontinent?",
a:"Indus Valley Civilisation",
b:"Aryans and the Vedic Culture",
c:"Mauryan Empire",
d:"Gupta Empire",
correct:"a"
},
{
question:"Who designed the periodic table?",
a:"Dmitri Mendeleev",
b:"Gregor Mendel",
c:"Albert Einstein",
d:"John Dalton",
correct:"a"
},
{
question:"Which gas is also known as laughing gas?",
a:"Helium",
b:"Hydrogen",
c:"Carbon monoxide",
d:"Nitrous Oxide",
correct:"d"
}
];
